We've talked a lot about looking at data,
之前我们主要在将如何关注数据
capturing metrics, and how to work through ways to solve what we want to measure.
获取指标 如何找到我们所要衡量的方面
But when it comes to putting those metrics to work,
但是如果要将这些指标应用于实际业务
well, we need to add in another layer of complexity.
我们还需要考虑一层很复杂的因素
We talk a lot about segmenting and marketing.
之前我们提过市场细分与营销
So it's time that we evaluate how we begin to measure our customer segments.
现在 我们要深入讲解如何开始衡量客户群体
Consumer segment is really a way of dividing up
客户细分是指将你的客户划分成
your consumers into different groups of like people.
行为相似的不同群体
We may have many segments,
我们可以用很多不同的客户群体
and these segments can all perform differently.
这些群体的行为都不相同
So really, we need to begin to measure how one segment performs against a piece of data.
所以我们应该以单项标准来衡量某个客户群体
We may have a lifetime value that is different
比如 对于我们的业务来说 每个客户群体的
for each segment of consumers that come to our business.
LTV 可能是不同的
Let's get on the same page.
我们来统一定义
Segmentation is really a process of taxonomy.
客户群体实际上是一种细分法
It's a way that we divide something into parts, and really,
就是我们如何将一个整体划分为多个细分部分
it's a way that we begin to separate the market into sub-markets.
这样 市场也随之划分成了多个细分市场
Generally, within a consumer segment,
通常 在一个细分群体内部
you have homogeneous within, and heterogeneous between.
我们能找到很多共通点 在群体之间 则有很多区分点
This really means that good segments are going to have
也就是说 一个有效的细分应该是将行为非常类似
customers that are all very similar within that segment,
的客户划分到了一个群体
and very dissimilar to customers of other segments.
而这些客户与其他群体的客户非常不同
We can have segments based on attributes of customers,
我们可以根据客户特征来划分
such as those that we looked at earlier,
像之前的例子
ones who'd like sports or fitness.
有运动人士或者健身人士
We may also have segments based on very simple business rules.
我们也可以根据非常简单的商业规则来细分
For example, you might view your segment as those that use your product a lot,
比如 经常购买你的产品的人
a little bit, very little,
偶尔买的 几乎不买的
or not at all.
完全不买的
Alternatively, you get segment based on recency,
或者 你也可以根据时间远近、频率、
frequency, and monetary variables.
或者价值变量 来划分
How recently did a customer purchase?
某个客户最近一次的购买是在什么时候？
How frequently does a customer purchase?
某个客户的购买频率是怎样的？
How much did they spend?
他消费了多少钱？
We could take those consumer groups,
我们可以把这些类似的客户
those that frequent purchase,
比如 经常购买的
those that spend a lot,
消费额较大的
or those that we see often,
经常访问的
and create segments for them.
把他们划分成各自不同的群体
Segments are important in marketing,
细分对于市场营销来说很重要
and just as important in our marketing analytics.
对于市场分析 也是非常重要的
If we can find all the people that are alike, well,
如果你可以定位到很多相同或者类似的人
then we can assume that their behaviors are also very much alike.
我们就可以预设他们的行为也将非常类似
So when we measure things and make decisions,
所以我们做决策的时候
we can expect that those decisions impact that entire group similarly.
也就可以假设这些决策会自然而然地影响到整个群体
Take abandonment for example,
拿丢弃率举例子
or churn, or cancellation,
或者任何可以代表客户撤离漏斗的指标
or any metric that suggests customers are leaving your funnel.
比如 客户流失率 退订率 等
That metric exists as an aggregate.
这个指标实际上是一个聚合
So you can say, "Our business has a 10 percent churn rate."
比如 你说 公司的客户流失率是 10%
In other words, we can expect for every 10 customers we get,
也就是说 10 个客户里
to have one of them go away.
有 1 个会流失
But what if we slice that data by segment?
但是如果按照客户群体来看流失率呢？
What have we discovered, that customers who use our product five times,
我们居然发现 对于购买过 5 次产品的那些客户
there are in a high-use segment,
即 属于高频客户
have only a one percent churn rate.
才有 1% 的流失率
Well, that tells us a completely different story.
那情况就完全不一样了！
Now, just as we said,
就想之前说的
there is no one size of framework.
没有一个万能的框架
There is no one size fits all customer.
同样 也没有一个万能的客户群体指标
By understanding these segments,
了解了客户细分后
we can really look at data in a more granular fashion,
我们可以用更多面的方式来关注指标
while still making it actionable.
同时也保证了指标的可执行性
With that churn rate,
有了这个流失率数据
we know that we can invest in ways to influence other customer groups,
我们就找准了方向 可以通过一些方式让其他客户群体
maybe the medium use groups,
比如 中频客户
to arrive at higher usage of our product,
转为 高频客户
because we know that if we can move them into that group,
因为根据数据 一旦他们成为了高频客户
the churn rate will go down.
流失率就会降低
I can't take action on the results of an individual person.
如果你分析单个客户的行为 是不会得出这些结果的
That's why segmentation is important.
这就是为什么划分客户群体很重要
If we look at one person,
如果单看每一个客户
that's far too granular.
就实在太细了
So we need to take them as a group so that we can
我们要把他们当做不同的群体
understand the similar behaviors that link them together.
才能理解是什么样的共通行为将他们联系在一起
Now, segments reveal themselves differently.
客户群体都各不相同
You may have a segment sensitive to price,
有些可能对价格敏感
a segment that prefers a particular marketing channel,
有些对某个特定的营销渠道的接受程度很高
or a segment that requires a certain style of communication.
有些会需要使用一些特定的沟通风格
Start thinking about how you can layer segmentation into your analytics.
从现在开始 思考你如何能将客户细分与分析结合在一起
What insights might it provide?
客户细分能提供什么样的洞察？
What will it reveal?
能发现什么样的事实？
The more data that we can attribute to a segment,
我们能发现关于某个群体的越多数据
the better decisions we can make in influencing
就越能作出影响他们的好决策
that segment to achieve our marketing objectives.
从而达到我们的业务目标